So after having a look at has set and when would you use that right now comes
working with reset I've created a class for you appropriately called it working
with a reset have the main method ready and now we move on and just create a
reset the generic argument we can use strings or integers let's use an integer
this time I'll just call it a set for example and new reset and now what would
happen is reset is one of only two collection classes in Java which are sorted
in natural ordering by default right and you'll see that shortly now let's go
ahead and do that I'll say set to date and that's it numbers because it's an
integer only set right set to date and that's it's probably based a few
times that we have some data to play around with I'll say some numbers
here okay now if you just go in and print that out I'll just use a for each the
Java it for each now I'll say set got for each and again system root out method
reference say a print and then and you will see why I said it is sorted by default
in natural ordering that in you run this and have a look at my screen it says
to first although you added to as the second last element because it went on
sorting that in natural ordering right by default you don't need to do that
right yourself so 24567 3 1 3 and then 2 8 3 4 8 9 has the biggest largest and
at the last number right so that is what you get with at least and like it
has said now it won't allow duplicates I'll say set to date let's say 3 1 3
again but you won't get an error I'll say no error but would not be duplicated
you'll not find a duplicate value not be added and that's why you can just put it
in a if because it has a return type of Boolean if you want to check whether it
was added or not just add this statement in an if condition and then you're
good to go but for now you see only 1 3 1 3 here because see that is where why
because we're using a tree set which is a subclass of the set interface if you
were using any subclass of less duplicate values are allowed you know that
that's a difference so now when would you as a Java developer prefer using a
tree set the first thing is when your requirement allows you to not store
duplicate values they should not be stored the second requirement is you are
concerned with the ordering and the sorting now because it gives you a collection
which is sorted in natural ordering and the third thing you saw that it does
the sorting by itself you don't need to do it right so those are the conditions
so next in the next video we're going to look at maps and in which situations
you're going to use which kind of a map